northseattle.edu 2019-05-28

# Seattle Colleges

Seattle Community Colleges Privacy Notice 

Contents

  * Introduction
  * Information collected and how it is used
  * Personal information and choice
  * Public access to information
  * Nondisclosure of certain personal information
    * Credit Card Payment
    * Degree Audit
    * Financial Aid Inquiry
    * Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit
    * Registration
    * Registration Appointment
    * Schedule Planner
    * Student Address Change
    * Student PIN Change
    * Student Schedule
    * Unofficial Transcript
    * Student ID (SID) Lookup
    * e-Learning
  * Review and correction of personally identifiable information
  * Cookies
  * Security
  * Disclaimer
  * Seattle Community Colleges contact information

Introduction

Thank you for visiting the Seattle Community Colleges website and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use, and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of Seattle Community Colleges website. This notice covers the following topics: 

  * Information Collected and How it is Used
  * Personal Information and Choice
  * Public Access to Information
  * Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information
  * Cookies
  * Security
  * Disclaimer
  * Contact Information

Top of page

Information Collected and How it is Used

Information collected if you only browse this site.  
If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit: 

  1. The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (for example, _xcompany.com_ or _seattlecolleges.edu_ ); 
  2. The type of browser and operating system you used
  3. The date and time you visited this site
  4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site
  5. The website you visited prior to coming to this website.

The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Seattle Community Colleges only to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Seattle Community Colleges analyzes the website logs to determine how our website is being used, so that we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public. 

What we collect if you volunteer information.  
If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following additional information will be collected: 

  * The e-mail address, and contents of e-mail, for those who communicate with us via e-mail.
  * Information volunteered in response to a survey.
  * Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose.

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. 

We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used. 

Top of page

Personal Information and Choice

You may choose whether to provide personal information online.

Personal information is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information. 

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse seattlecolleges.edu and read or download any information provided on the site. 

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law. 

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Public Records Officer, Connie Palmer. Contact Information is available at the end of this document in the Contact information section. 

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access. 

Top of page

Public Access to Information

In the State Of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws. 

All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. Statue [RCW 42.17. 260(1)](http://search.leg.wa.gov/wslrcw/RCW%20%2042%20%20TITLE/RCW%20%2042%20.%2017%20%20CHAPTER/RCW%20%2042%20.%2017%20.260.htm) states that: 

Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section [RCW 42.17.260(6)], RCW 42.17.310, 42.17.315, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.17.310 and 42.17.315 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing. 

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency’s disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control. 

The complete Revised Code of Washington (RCW) is available at: [wsl.leg.wa.gov/wsladm/rcw.cfm](http://wsl.leg.wa.gov/wsladm/rcw.cfm)

Top of page

Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information

You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the Web-enabled applications that are described below.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Seattle Community Colleges from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, address, telephone number, date and place of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information. 

Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act. 
  * [RCW 42.17.310](http://search.leg.wa.gov/pub/textsearch/ViewRoot.asp?Action=Html&Item=15&X=815105327&p=1) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law. 

Top of page

Credit Card Payment

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to pay tuition and fees over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to pay your tuition and fees in person. 

Degree Audit

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to perform a degree audit of your records over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display a degree audit of your records over the Web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person or by mail. 

Financial Aid Inquiry

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your financial aid status over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to give you your financial aid status over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person or by mail. 

Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Leaning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records either in person or by mail. 

Top of page

Registration

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you will have to register for classes in person. 

Registration Appointment

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment information address in person or by mail. 

Schedule Planner

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to check requisites while using schedule planner. The information is required in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to verify your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling into those classes. 

Top of page

Student Address Change

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have to change your address in person or by mail. 

Student PIN Change

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your personal identification number over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your PIN over the Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person or by mail.

Top of page

Student Schedule

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify you identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person or by mail.

Unofficial Transcript

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person or by mail.

Top of page

Student ID (SID) Number Lookup

Seattle Community Colleges may require you to provide certain personal information in order to lookup your Student ID Number over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to lookup your Student ID Number over the Web. 

e-Learning

The Seattle Colleges e-Learning sites allow students an online option to enroll in our Colleges, register for classes and pay tuition and fees. Personal information must be collected from the student and verified by the registrar's office in order to verify that the student has met the requirements set by the Colleges to enroll and register for any given class. 

  * Establish a student's residency status in order to accurately calculate fees.
  * Process Credit Card payment of tuition and fees.

If you do not wish to provide this information online you may enroll and/or register in person at any of our three Colleges.

Top of page

Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information

You can review any personally identifiable information the Seattle Community Colleges collects about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections ([RCW 43.105.310](http://search.leg.wa.gov/pub/textsearch/ViewRoot.asp?Action=Html&Item=1&X=815134736&p=1)). 

Top of page

Cookies

seattlecolleges.edu does not use client-side cookies to customize your browsing experience with seattlecolleges.edu except for the following web applications: 

  * Online Student Kiosk
  * Online Instructor's Briefcase
  * Employee's Earning History

Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser.

Cookies created on your computer by using this website do not contain personally identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security. We use the cookie feature to store the following information on your computer: 

  * Session login information
  * Limited personal information, such as name

**seattlecolleges.edu** does use server-side cookies to identify your browsing session and thus customize your browsing experience. We use the cookie feature only to store a randomly generated identifying tag on our server that identifies your computer and session. 

Applets are tools downloaded to your computer to work with the software you have. Applets are intended to enhance your browsing experience by enabling you to view information in a unique manner or nable access to information that your computer would otherwise be unable to access without the applet. 

You are not required to use applets to browse this site. Choosing not to accept applets will not affect your general ability to browse this website and download information, but may adversely affect how information appears on your computer or your ability to view the information that the applet is intended to support. 

Top of page

Security

The Seattle Community Colleges, as developer and manager of seattlecolleges.edu, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Seattle Community Colleges. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession. 

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via Seattle Community Colleges websites.

Top of page

Disclaimer

The Seattle Community Colleges website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Seattle Community Colleges website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

Top of page

Seattle Community Colleges Contact Information

You may contact Seattle Community Colleges as follows:

  * To review or correct your personal information contact the registrar's office for the college in which you are enrolled.

Diane Coleman, Director of Admission/Registrar  
Seattle Central Community College  
1701 Broadway  
Seattle, WA 98122  
Telephone:(206) 587-3842  
email: [dcoleman@sccd.ctc.edu](mailto:dcoleman@sccd.ctc.edu)

Kim Manderbach, Director of Admission/Registrar  
South Seattle Community College  
6000 16th Avenue S.W.  
Seattle, WA 98106  
Telephone:(206) 764-5378  
email: [kmanderb@sccd.ctc.edu](mailto:kmanderb@sccd.ctc.edu)

Marci Myer, Director of Admission/Registrar  
North Seattle Community College  
9600 College Way North  
Seattle, WA 98103  
Telephone:(206) 527-3669  
email: [mmyer@sccd.ctc.edu](mailto:mmyer@sccd.ctc.edu)

  * To review or correct your personal information contact the Public Records Officer at the District Office.

Patricia Paquette, Public Records Officer  
Seattle Community Colleges  
1500 Harvard Ave.  
Seattle, WA 98122  
Telephone:(206) 587-4105  
FAX: (206) 287-5564  
email: [ppaquette@sccd.ctc.edu](mailto:ppaquette@sccd.ctc.edu)

Top of page

updated: 06/18/2009
